<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Slide on Suneet Agrawal</title>
    <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/categories/slide/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Slide on Suneet Agrawal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/categories/slide/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The power of Camera APIs and OpenGL all together</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/slides/the-power-of-camera-apis-and-opengl-all-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/slides/the-power-of-camera-apis-and-opengl-all-together/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Are you using the best out of your device camera and GPU in your app?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do you know how camera frames are drawn on the screen?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do you think your camera should do way more than just clicking a picture?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Did you ever try to process the frames like applying filters or beautification before previewing it?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How a view or camera frame is drawn on the screen?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What is OpenGL? How OpenGL controls GPU rendering?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;What are vertex and fragment shaders? How do they affect the camera frame and preview?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;How can we modify the camera frames between camera APIs and previewing? What all can we do with that?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Well, let&amp;rsquo;s get all these questions answered in the presentation below with our experiences and challenges we&amp;rsquo;ve faced.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Low Level Design : Tic-Tac-Toe</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/slides/low-level-design-tic-tac-toe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/slides/low-level-design-tic-tac-toe/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;System designing is the process of designing system elements such as architectures, modules, components, different interfaces of those components. Its the process of defining the lowest level entities in a software. It is the backbone of any software.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How can I migrate my Android code from Java to Kotlin?</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/slides/how-can-i-migrate-my-android-code-from-java-to-kotlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/slides/how-can-i-migrate-my-android-code-from-java-to-kotlin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In continuation of the previews session for &lt;a href=&#34;https://startup.google.com/&#34;&gt;Google Accelerator program&lt;/a&gt; on the topic &lt;a href=&#34;https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/slides/java-or-kotlin-what-do-you-use&#34;&gt;Java or Kotlin. what do you use?&lt;/a&gt; today we are going to look at how can you migrate the codebase from java to Kotlin and what are the common mistake made by developers while doing the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Java or Kotlin, What do you use?</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/slides/java-or-kotlin-what-do-you-use/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/slides/java-or-kotlin-what-do-you-use/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kotlin is something which was introduced as an official language for Android development in Google I/O 2017. Since then it has grown and evolved a lot. It has multiple benefits and on top of everything, it&amp;rsquo;s really easy to use.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Object-Oriented Programming (OOP) Concepts</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/slides/object-oriented-programming-oop-concepts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/slides/object-oriented-programming-oop-concepts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Object-oriented programming (OOP) concepts are something which are fundamentals of any Object-oriented programming language. These concepts give you the power to structure your code in such a way that it&amp;rsquo;s well optimized, reusable, efficient, future proof and much more.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cut your APK Size with features on demand</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/slides/cut-your-apk-size-with-features-on-demand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/slides/cut-your-apk-size-with-features-on-demand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Do APK or app size matters?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Does a user think about the APK size before downloading it?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Does a user think about space, an app occupying on the phone?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Is your App size is more than just a few MBs?&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What if we provide very basic functionality and let the user decide whether he wants the advanced or additional functionality or not?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
