<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Java on Suneet Agrawal</title>
    <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/tags/java/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Java on Suneet Agrawal</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/tags/java/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vector in Java</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/vector-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/vector-in-java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Vectors are an important data structure in Java programming that are used to store and manipulate collections of elements. A vector is similar to an array, but with some additional features that make it more flexible and convenient to use. In this blog, we will explore the basics of vectors in Java, how they differ from arrays, and how to use them in your programs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ArrayList in Java</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/arraylist-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/arraylist-in-java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ArrayList is one of the most commonly used data structures in Java. It provides a dynamic array implementation that allows you to add and remove elements from the list. The size of the ArrayList can also be dynamically changed based on the number of elements added or removed from the list. In this blog, we will dive into the details of ArrayList in Java, how it works, and some examples of how to use it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Map Implementation in Java</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/map-implementation-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/map-implementation-in-java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Java provides a powerful data structure called Map, which is used to store key-value pairs. A Map is a collection of unique keys and their corresponding values, and it provides efficient methods to add, remove, and access elements in constant time.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Set Implementation in Java</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/set-implementation-in-java/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/set-implementation-in-java/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Set is an interface in Java that represents a collection of unique elements, meaning that no two elements in a set can be the same. Java provides several implementations of Set, each with its own unique features and trade-offs. In this blog post, we will explore the different implementations of Set in Java and their use cases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
