<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Unity on Suneet Agrawal</title>
    <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/tags/unity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Unity on Suneet Agrawal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/tags/unity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Android text sharing to Whatsapp contact in Unity</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/native-android-text-sharing-to-whatsapp-contact-in-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/native-android-text-sharing-to-whatsapp-contact-in-unity/</guid>
      <description>In the previous blogs, we learnt about how can we trigger native Android text, image or any other format file sharing in Unity App. A lot of you have asked me about how can we share some text directly to a WhatsApp contact.   If you have not read the previous medium posts, I would strongly recommend to read them first. You can read them on the links below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Android image sharing in Unity</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/native-android-image-sharing-in-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/native-android-image-sharing-in-unity/</guid>
      <description>In continuation to my previous medium post Native Android in Unity and Native Android text sharing in Unity, will consider another example of native Android screenshot sharing functionality in the unity app.   If you have not read the previous medium posts, I would strongly recommend to read them first. You can read them on the links below.  Native Android in Unity Native Android text sharing in Unity   As the number says, an image gains more attention than a normal text while sharing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Android image sharing in Unity using FileProvider</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/native-android-image-sharing-in-unity-using-fileprovider/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/native-android-image-sharing-in-unity-using-fileprovider/</guid>
      <description>While implementing native sharing using my previous post, Native Android image sharing in Unity we saw an exception “android.os.FileUriExposedException” in Android 8 (Oreo) and above.   Since Google changed the sharing way using FileProvider to make it more secure, we can not share the file object directly to any other Application. We need to use the FileProvider and grant read URI permission to make it accessible for any other app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Android in Unity</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/native-android-in-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/native-android-in-unity/</guid>
      <description>While developing unity games in C# targeting android platform, we always want to use few native android features in our game. These features can be showing notifications on certain actions in the game or can be sharing the high score with other players and inviting them to try our game using android native share. Android gives us all the possibilities to achieve these native android functionalities in unity app using C#.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Android text sharing in Unity</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/native-android-text-sharing-in-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/native-android-text-sharing-in-unity/</guid>
      <description>In continuation to my previous medium post Native Android in Unity, will consider another example of native Android text sharing functionality in the unity app. This is a very common requirement in any unity app targeting Android platform to share the high score or challenge other players with a text message or a screenshot of the high score. The sharing can be done via any of the app available on the user’s device which supports sharing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Android text sharing to particular app in Unity</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/native-android-text-sharing-to-particular-app-in-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/native-android-text-sharing-to-particular-app-in-unity/</guid>
      <description>In the previous posts Native Android text sharing in Unity and Native Android image sharing in Unity we learnt about how to share some text or screenshot to other apps in a Unity app targeting Android platforms. In this post will target sharing the same text or image to some particular app directly.   If you have not read the previous medium posts, I would strongly recommend to read them first.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>