<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gists on Suneet Agrawal</title>
    <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gists on Suneet Agrawal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>UIView ClickListener : Swift</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/uiview-clicklistener-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/uiview-clicklistener-swift/</guid>
      <description>
This particular script will help you to implement a Click listener to all UIView and its subclasses in a clean way.   For further explaination on how this works, please read the article UIView ClickListener : Swift.  
   (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});   &amp;lt;&amp;lt; All Gists   Native Android in Unity &amp;gt;&amp;gt;    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Android : Share message directly to whatsapp contact</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/android-share-message-directly-to-whatsapp-contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/android-share-message-directly-to-whatsapp-contact/</guid>
      <description>
This particular script will help you to implement a text message sharing directly to a WhatsApp contact in Android.   For further explaination on how this works, please read the article Android : Share message directly to whatsapp contact.  
   (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});   &amp;lt;&amp;lt; All Gists   Native Android in Unity &amp;gt;&amp;gt;    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Android image sharing in Unity</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/native-android-image-sharing-in-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/native-android-image-sharing-in-unity/</guid>
      <description>This particular script will help you to implement native Android image sharing in Unity.  We use all the native classes of Android in Unity using AndroidJavaClass and AndroidJavaObject and perform the Android&#39;s ACTION_SEND with EXTRA_SUBJECT, EXTRA_TEXT and EXTRA_STREAM. The content type is set to image/png in the below example but you can change it to any type and share other formats also.   For further explaination on how this works, please read the article Native Android screenshot/image sharing in Unity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Android image sharing in Unity using FileProvider</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/native-android-image-sharing-in-unity-using-fileprovider/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/native-android-image-sharing-in-unity-using-fileprovider/</guid>
      <description>This particular script will help you to implement native Android image sharing using Android&#39;s FileProvider in Unity. This is a fix for “android.os.FileUriExposedException” in Android 8 (Oreo) and above.  We use all the native classes of Android in Unity using AndroidJavaClass and AndroidJavaObject and perform the Android&#39;s ACTION_SEND with EXTRA_SUBJECT, EXTRA_TEXT and EXTRA_STREAM. The content type is set to image/png in the below example but you can change it to any type and share other formats also.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Android in Unity</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/native-android-in-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/native-android-in-unity/</guid>
      <description>
This particular script will help you to implement basic native Android in Unity.  This show an example of showing a native Android&#39;s Toast in unity using AndroidJavaClass and AndroidJavaObject.   For further explaination on how this works, please read the article Native Android in Unity.  
   (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});   &amp;lt;&amp;lt; All Gists   Native Android text sharing in Unity &amp;gt;&amp;gt;    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Android text sharing in Unity</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/native-android-text-sharing-in-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/native-android-text-sharing-in-unity/</guid>
      <description>
This particular script will help you to implement native Android text sharing in Unity.  We use all the native classes of Android in Unity using AndroidJavaClass and AndroidJavaObject and perform the Android&#39;s ACTION_SEND with EXTRA_SUBJECT and EXTRA_TEXT.   For further explaination on how this works, please read the article Native Android text sharing in Unity.      (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});   &amp;lt;&amp;lt; All Gists   Native Android image sharing in Unity &amp;gt;&amp;gt;    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Android text sharing to particular app in Unity</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/native-android-text-sharing-to-particular-app-in-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/native-android-text-sharing-to-particular-app-in-unity/</guid>
      <description>This particular script will help you to implement native Android text sharing to a particular app in Unity.  We use all the native classes of Android in Unity using AndroidJavaClass and AndroidJavaObject and perform the Android&#39;s ACTION_SEND with EXTRA_SUBJECT and EXTRA_TEXT, and share the content to a particular app with package name.   For further explaination on how this works, please read the article Native Android share to a particular app in Unity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native Android text sharing to Whatsapp contact in Unity</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/native-android-text-sharing-to-whatsapp-contact-in-unity/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/gists/native-android-text-sharing-to-whatsapp-contact-in-unity/</guid>
      <description>
This particular script will help you to implement a text message sharing directly to a WhatsApp contact in Unity.   For further explaination on how this works, please read the article Native Android text sharing to Whatsapp contact in Unity.  
   (adsbygoogle = window.adsbygoogle || []).push({});   &amp;lt;&amp;lt; All Gists   Native Android in Unity &amp;gt;&amp;gt;    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>