<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JavaScript on Suneet Agrawal</title>
    <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/tags/javascript/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JavaScript on Suneet Agrawal</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/tags/javascript/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Function Expression : JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/function-expression-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/function-expression-javascript/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript is a dynamic and versatile programming language that allows developers to create complex and dynamic applications. One of the key features of JavaScript is its ability to use functions as first-class citizens. This means that functions can be assigned to variables, passed as arguments to other functions, and even returned as values from functions. In this article, we&#39;ll take a closer look at function expressions in JavaScript and explore how they can be used in your code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JavaScript ‘For’ Loop</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/javascript-for-loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/javascript-for-loop/</guid>
      <description>Loops are an essential part of any programming language, and JavaScript is no exception. One of the most common loops used in JavaScript is the for loop. In this blog, we will focus on the for loop in JavaScript and how it can be used to iterate over an array or object. What is a for loop? A for loop is a programming construct used to repeat a section of code for a specified number of times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Array Operations in JavaScript (Push, Pop, Shift and Unshift)</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/array-operations-in-javascript-push-pop-shift-unshift/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/array-operations-in-javascript-push-pop-shift-unshift/</guid>
      <description>JavaScript is a powerful programming language that offers several ways to manipulate arrays, which are one of the most commonly used data structures in JavaScript. Four important array manipulation methods are push, pop, shift, and unshift. These methods allow you to add and remove elements from the beginning or end of an array. In this blog, we will discuss these methods and their usage in JavaScript. Push Method in JS The push() method is used to add one or more elements to the end of an array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Equality (&#39;=&#39; vs &#39;==&#39; vs &#39;===&#39;) in JavaScript</title>
      <link>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/equality-in-javascript/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://agrawalsuneet.github.io/blogs/equality-in-javascript/</guid>
      <description>In JavaScript, there are three types of equality operators: =, ==, and ===. Each of these operators has a different purpose and can lead to different results when used. Understanding the differences between these operators is essential for writing efficient and reliable code in JavaScript. = Operator in JS The = operator is used for assigning values to variables. It is called the assignment operator. When using the = operator, the value on the right side of the operator is assigned to the variable on the left side.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
